

• Mexico City, Mexico

in Ricardo Ruiz

gaanzz11@gmail.com

★ gitlab.com/Ricardoengitlab

github.com/Ricardoengithub

(+52) 5620278551

SUMMARY

I have 3 years of professional experience in sectors such as insurance, real estate and e-commerce. I mainly work with Javascript (with experience in React and React Native), Python (with experience in Django) and Java. As a Computer Scientist I can get involved in any area of development including research however I am mainly interested in the front end.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full stack developer at Badak Soluciones

June 2022 - Present

I gave maintenance to two applications (web/mobile) that are used in Zacatecas, Mexico that allow the client (AB InBev) to obtain information on the sale of alcohol in different establishments in the state. I had to create an improved version of the app to be used during the Qatar 2022 world cup which was published in the Play Store which includes new features such as being able to be used offline and sync the data when conected.

React Native / React / Javascript / Firebase / MongoDB / Material UI

Front end developer at GNP Seguros

April 2021 - February 2022

UI for an insurance company where agents can fill all data required for several types of insurances based on their client's needs to get the cost and try to make an offer.

React / Javascript / Redux / Material UI / Team Management

Full stack developer at M22

October 2020 - February 2021

UI for a real estate company where people can view details and availability of several places for make purchase agreement. All the data updates in real time and the content is modified from a Content Management System(CMS).

React / Javascript / Strapi JS / QGIS / GraphQL / PostgreSQL

Full stack developer at Ultra maratón sierra mixe

January 2020 - September 2020

This is a client's project on the automation of the processes involved in the realization of a marathon race such as registration, marketing and payment.

React / Javascript / Google Firebase / Bootstrap

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SOFT SKILLS

Advanced: Javascript, React, HTML, CSS Communication
Teamwork

Intermediate: React Native, Python, Django, Java, Bootstrap

Adaptability
Problem-solving

Basic: NextJS, Gatsby, GraphQL, StrapiJS, Golang, NodeJS, Interpersonal skills

Typescript, Angular, React Native, MongoDB Time management

Leadership

Others: Flutter, Dart, Oracle SQL, C#, C, Unity, Racket, Attention to detail

Haskell Organization

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science

National Autonomous University of Mexico

Relevant Coursework: Automata Theory, Computer Architecture, Algorithm Analysis, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Data Structures, Relational Databases